

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Delivery Manager seeking roles in Delivery Management, Business Analysis, Project Management, Customer Relationship, Program Management, User Acceptance Testing, Project Delivery, Content Development, Application Development, Feasibility Studies, Sales Support



Total Experience: 13 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: PG Diploma [Cartography Gis]

Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Designation: DELIVERY MANAGER

Current Company: TCS (IGNIO PRODUCT)

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Canada, INDIA, United Kingdom (UK)
Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Project Mgr-IT/Software

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Delivery Manager, Project Manager, Delivery Management, Business Analysis, Project Management, Customer Relationship, Program Management, Budgeting, Project Delivery, Content Development, Application Management, Project Delivery, Content Development, Project Delivery, Content Develo

Development, Feasibility Studies, Sales Suppor

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21

21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

13+ Years of experience in the field of IT Industry in various domains with extensive experience in handling the roles of Delivery Manager, Project Manager, Business Analyst and Technical Lead. Currently handling Delivery for 5 accounts and a single point of contact to the customers

Work Experience

TCS (IGNIO PRODUCT) as DELIVERY MANAGER

Jan 2007 to Till Date

Growth Path-

DELIVERY MANAGER 2017 - Present PROJECT MANAGER 2013 - 2016 BUSINESS ANALYST 2009 - 2012 TECHNICAL LEAD 2007 - 2008

Establishes strategic relationships with each customer that transcends the tactical implementation details, thus ensuring appropriate

focus on long-term customer objectives.

- * Serves as the first level of escalation point beyond the Project Manager for all services delivery activity to assigned customers. Leads
- project teams in the resolution of customer project issues, negotiates win/win agreements, escalating project/project issues effectively.
- * Manages a portfolio of projects. Ensures that the projects deliver the value/ROI expected of the engagement, including quality, budget, and timelines.
- * Acts as a keyliaison with assigned customers on project implementation costs and modifications, general status communication and

escalated issues. Conducts regular delivery reviews to manage project related credits and mitigate cost and schedule overruns to

ensure high customer satisfaction.

- * Identifies new opportunities within the customer base and provides sales support during the sales cycle as needed.
- * Reviews and approves all SOWs and CRs, prior to submission to SOW Desk. Responsible for all estimates, project structure and project governance.
- * Proactively manages project risks for all assigned accounts.
- * Maintains a trusted advisor status with customers and participates in customer s strategic planning. Serves as the primary member

of the project Steering Committee.

* Responsible for maintaining accurate revenue forecasts for assigned accounts and projects.

4

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

- * Maintains a billable utilization and manages the forecast of that utilization.
- * Collaborates and shares project level insight with Account Team (CEs, SPs, Management, etc.) to allow for a collaborative relationship that increases customer's perception of the value JDAbrings to their business in order to expand future business opportunities.

Orchestrate internal resources across JDA to give the customer an enhanced experience across touch-points.

- * Builds a trusted group of referenceable customers who will vouch for JDA
- * Provides support to Project Managers; coaching and mentoring on major issues and policy conflicts, helps remove

in maintaining accurate revenue forecasts, is active in the scope planning and approves scope changes.

TCS (Global Application and Development) Client: GSK Bengaluru

PROJECT MANAGER 2013 - 2016

- * Manage a portfolio of complex initiatives that span one or multiple lines of business.
- * Provide on-site leadership for project team by building and motivating team members to meet project goals, adhering to their responsibilities and project milestones.
- * Full project life cycle ownership: successful project delivery will include full implementation from initiation to deployment for one

major or several minor initiatives simultaneously.

- * Report on project success criteria results, metrics, test and deployment management activities.
- * Work creatively and analytically in a problem-solving environment demonstrating teamwork, innovation and excellence
- * Participate in establishing practices, templates, policies, tools and partnerships to expand and mature these capabilities for the organization.
- * Prepare estimates and detailed project plan for all phases of the project.
- * Procure adequate resources to achieve project objectives in planned timeframes.
- * Manage the day-to-day project activities and resources and chairs the project management team meetings.
- * Monitor staff performance and complete performance reviews
- $^{\star} \ Provide \ status \ reporting \ regarding \ project \ milestones, \ deliverable, \ dependencies, \ risks \ and \ issues, \ communicating$ across leadership.

 * Understand interdependencies between technology, operations and business needs.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from JNTU College of Engineering, Hyderabad in 2006

PG: PG Diploma (Cartography Gis) from Annamalai University in 2019

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
SCORM,e-Learning, NICE &RPA		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Proficient			✓
Telugu	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.